Guide to the Priya Kambli photographs, 2006-2012 RL.11697
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Priya Kambli photographs
2006-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11697
2.0 Linear Feet 2 boxes 40 color inkjet prints 17 x 22 inches
Collection consists of forty 17x24 inch color inkjet prints from a body of work titled Color Falls Down by artist Priya Kambli, who emigrated from India to the U.S. at the age of eighteen. Sometimes resembling diptychs, the images juxtapose and recontextualize family photographs, personal objects such as clothing, spoons, and earrings, and contemporary self-portraits, exploring themes of migration, cross-cultural understanding, women and family, identity, and memory. This work received the 2018 ADA Collection Award for Women Documentarians. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Paper size is 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; individual image sizes vary and are listed in the entries.
Arrangement
Arranged in original order as assigned by the photographer.
Biographical Note
Artist Priya Kambli began her creative career when she emigrated to the United States from India at the age of 18, a few years after the death of her parents. Her work is informed by the loss of her parents, her experience as a migrant, and the inheritance of family photographs she brought with her to the U.S. Kambli received her BFA from the University of Louisiana at Lafayette and her MFA from the University of Houston. Currently, she is a Professor of Art at Truman State University in Kirksville, Missouri. In 2008, Kambli received PhotoLucida's Book Award for "Color Falls Down," which was later published in 2010. The work also received the 2018 Archive of Documentary Arts Award for Emerging Women Documentarians.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Images may only be used for educational, non-commercial purposes; any other use requires the photographer's permission.
Provenance
The Priya Kambli photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The photographs in this collection were printed on Harmon by Hahnemuhle Gloss Baryta Warmtone paper, using an Epson 7800 printer and Archival Epson ink.
Content Description
Collection consists of forty 17x24 inch color inkjet prints from a body of work titled Color Falls Down by artist Priya Kambli, who emigrated from India to the U.S. Sometimes resembling diptychs, the images juxtapose and recontextualize family photographs, personal objects such as clothing, spoons, and earrings, and contemporary self-portraits, exploring themes of migration, cross-cultural understanding, women and family, identity, and memory.
From the artist's statement: "At age 18, a couple of years after the death of my parents, I moved from India to the United States with all my belongings in one suitcase. My photographs, which are rooted in my fascination with my parents, visually express the notion of transience and split cultural identity caused by the act of migration. In Color Falls Down these issues are seen through the lens of my own personal history and cultural identity. I re-contextualize and alter my family snapshots and personal artifacts to reveal the correlations between generations, cultures and memory."
This work received the 2018 ADA Collection Award for Women Documentarians. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
East Indians -- Portraits; East Indians -- United States -- Ethnic identity; Families -- Photographs; Families -- India -- Photographs; Self-perception in art; Women immigrants -- United States; Women photographers -- United States; India -- Emigration and immigration; India -- Social life and customs; United States -- Emigration and immigration; Color photographs; Digital prints; Inkjet prints; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Kambli, Priya
- Color Falls Down, 2006-2012; 40 prints
  - Mama (Dadi Aaji, Dada Aajooba and Muma), 2012; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0001)
  - Muma (Dress), 2012; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0002)
  - Baba (Muma's Bangles), 2012; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0003)
  - Aaji, 2012; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0004)
  - Sona and Me, 2012; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0005)
  - Muma, Baba, Sona and Me, 2011; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 8 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0006)
  - Muma (Dear Suresh), 2011; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0007)
  - Dadi Aaji and Mama, 2011; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0008)
  - Dadi Aaji and Dada Aajooba (Yellow Petals), 2011; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0009)
  - Me (Polpat and Tumeric), 2010; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0010)
  - Dada Aajooba and Muma, 2010; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0011)
  - Mama, 2010; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0012)
  - Me (Flour), 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0013)
  - Muma (Blue Dibiya), 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0014)
  - Kavi (Silver Chumcha), 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0015)
  - Aajooba, Aaji and Muma, 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0016)
  - Muma and Me (Gold Earrings), 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 8 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0017)
  - Baba, 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0018)
  - Me (Red Hearts), 2009; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0019)
  - Muma Baba and Me, 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 8 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0020)
  - Muma and Me (Cast Shadow), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 9 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0021)
  - Dada Aajooba Muma and Me, 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 9 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0022)
  - Dadi Aaji and Me, 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0023)
  - Me (Golden Dibiya), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0024)
  - Dada Aajooba and Me, 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0025)
  - Muma (Turmeric), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0026)
  - Me (Red), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0027)
  - Muma and Me (Red), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0028)
  - Me (Tonka and Turmeric), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0029)
  - Kavi, 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 8 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0030)
  - Dada Aajooba, Mama, Aaron and Kavi, 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0031)
  - Me (Orange), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0032)
  - Me (Inoculation), 2008; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0033)
  - Muma and Me (Henna), 2008; Paper size: 23 1/2 x 17 1/2 inches; image size: 20 x 16 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0034)
  - Muma and Me (Flowers), 2007; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0035)
  - Muma's, 2006; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0036)
  - Aajooba and Me, 2006; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0037)
  - Me Wrapped, 2006; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 10 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0038)
  - Aajooba and Me 2, 2006; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 8 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0039)
  - Muma and Baba, 2006; Paper size: 17 1/2 x 23 1/2 inches; image size: 8 x 22 inches (Box 1, Image RL.11697-P-0040)